Guide to the New-York Historical Society Collection of Geographic Images circa 1600-2006 PR 20
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: New York City Views - Manhattan, 50413
  - Subseries IC: MANHATTAN - FLAT MATERIALS- PHOTOS, 50556
    - Manhattan - Flat Material - Photos - Street Views, 217653
      - Named Streets, 218484
        - Broadway - 42nd Street north to 59th Street, 218175 (Folder FF209)
        - Broadway - 59th Street north to 100th Street, 218177 (Folder FF210)
        - Broadway - 100th Street and north, 218178 (Folder FF211)
        - Canal Street, 218179 (Folder FF212)
        - Cathedral Parkway SEE: West 110th Street, 218181 (Folder .)
        - Cedar Street, 218182 (Folder FF213)
        - Centre Street, 218184 (Folder FF214)
        - Central Park West and Central Park South, 218185 (Folder FF215)
        - Chambers Street, 218186 (Folder FF216)
        - Coenties Slip, 218191 (Folder FF217)
        - Columbus Circle, 218192 (Folder FF218)
        - Streets - C, 218187 (Folder FF219)
          Charles Street
          Chatham Street
          Cherry Street
          Cliff Street
          Columbus Avenue
        - Streets - D, 218193 (Folder FF220)
          Delancey Street
          Division Street
          Doyers Street
          Duane Street
          Dutch Street
          Dyckman Street
        - Streets - E, 218210 (Folder FF221)
          Edgar Street
          Essex Street
          Exchange Place
        - Streets - F, 218213 (Folder FF222)
          Fort George Avenue
          Frankfort Street
          Franklin Street
          Front Street
        - Fulton Street, 218214 (Folder FF223-224)
        - Streets - G, 218216 (Folder FF225)
          Gramercy Park East
          Gramercy Park North
          Grand Street
          Greeley Square
          Greenwich Street
        - Greene Street, 219163 (Folder FF226)
        - Streets - H, 218219 (Folder FF227)
          Hanover Square
          Harlem River Speedway
          Henderson Place
          Hester Street
        - Herald Square, 218220 (Folder FF228)
        - Hudson Street, 218222 (Folder FF229)
        - Streets - I, 218224 (Folder FF230)
          Irving Place
          Isham Street
        - John Street, 218225 (Folder FF231)
        - Streets - L, 218227 (Folder FF232)
          Lafayette Street
          Lexington Avenue
          Liberty Street
        - Madison Avenue, 218228 (Folder FF233-234)
        - Madison Square, 218230 (Folder FF235-236)
        - Maiden Lane, 218231 (Folder FF237)
        - Mulberry Street, 218233 (Folder FF238)
        - Streets - M, 218232 (Folder FF239)
          Manhattan Street
          Market Street
          Mott Street
        - Nassau Street, 218234 (Folder FF240)
        - Streets - N, 218235 (Folder FF241)
          New Street
          North Moore Street
        - Oliver Street, 218240 (Folder FF242)
        - Park Avenue - north to 42nd Street, 218241 (Folder FF243)
          includes photos of water mains beneath the streets.
        - Park Avenue - 42nd to 72nd Street, 219400 (Folder FF244-245)
        - Park Avenue - north of 72nd Street, 219402 (Folder FF246-247)
        - Park Place, 218254 (Folder FF248)
        - Park Row, 219403 (Folder FF249-250)
        - Pearl Street, 218255 (Folder FF251)
        - Streets - P, 218257 (Folder FF252)
          Pine Street
          Prince Street
        - Streets - R, 218258 (Folder FF253)
          Reade Street
          Rector Street
          Rose Street
        - Riverside Drive, 219397 (Folder FF254)
        - South Street, 218425 (Folder FF255)
        - State Street, 218426 (Folder FF256)
        - Streets - S, 218427 (Folder FF257)
          Separated Materials Note
          Striker's Row
          Stuyvesant Street
        - Streets - T, 218428 (Folder FF258)
          Thames Street
          Trinity Place
        - Union Square East, 218429 (Folder 259)
        - Union Square West, 218430 (Folder FF260)
        - University Place, 218431 (Folder 261)
        - Streets - V, 218432 (Folder FF262)
          Vanderbilt Avenue
          Varick Street
        - Wall Street, 218433 (Folder FF263-265)
        - Water Street, 221156 (Folder FF266)
        - West Broadway, 218438 (Folder FF267)
        - West Street, 218439 (Folder FF268)
        - William Street, 218471 (Folder FF269)
        - Worth Street, 218473 (Folder FF270)
        - Streets - W, 218436 (Folder FF271)
          Warren Street
          Waverly Place
          Weehawken Street
          West End Avenue
          Whitehall Street
        - York Avenue, 218476 (Folder FF272)
      - Numbered Streets, 218485
        - 3rd - 10th Street, 218486 (Folder FF273)
          West 3rd
          West 4th
          East 5th
          West 8th
          East 9th
          West 10th
        - East 14th, 218490 (Folder FF274 - FF275)
        - West 14th, 218491 (Folder FF276)
        - 16th - 22nd Street, 218492 (Folder FF277)
          East 16th
          East 17th
          East 19th
          East 20th
          West 21st
          West 22nd
        - East 23rd, 218498 (Folder FF278)
        - West 23rd, 218499 (Folder FF279 - FF279.5)
        - 30th - 33rd Street, 218604 (Folder FF280)
          West 30th Street
          West 31st Street
          East and West 32nd Street
          West 33rd Street
        - East and West 34th, 218606 (Folder FF281)
        - 35th - 40th Street, 218607 (Folder FF282)
          West 35th Street
          East 39th Street
          East and West 40th Street
        - East 42nd, 218608 (Folder FF283)
        - West 42nd, 218609 (Folder FF284)
        - 43rd - 44th Street, 218610 (Folder FF285)
          West 43rd Street
          West 44th Street
        - 45th - 46th Street, 218611 (Folder FF286)
          East and West 45th Street
          West 46th Street
        - 47th - 49th Street, 218612 (Folder FF287)
          West 47th Street
          East and West 48th Streets
          East and West 49th Streets
        - 50th - 55th Street, 218613 (Folder FF288)
          West 50th Street
          East 52nd Street
          West 53rd Street
          East and West 54th Street
          West 55th Street
        - 56th - 58th Street, 218614 (Folder FF289)
          West 56th Street
          East and West 57th Streets
          East and West 58th Streets
        - 60th - 78th Street, 218615 (Folder FF290)
          West 60th Street
          East 62nd Street
          West 64th Street
          East 67th Street
          West 72nd Street
          West 73rd Street
          East 78th Street
        - 80th - 94th Street, 218616 (Folder FF291)
          West 80th Street
          East 86th Street
          East 88th Street
        - 100th - 213th Street, 218618 (Folder FF292)
          West 100th Street
          East 120th Street
          West 121st Street
          West 131st Street
          West 133rd Street
          West 179th Street
          West 181st Street
          West 213th Street
        - First Avenue, 224347 (Folder FF293)
        - Third Avenue, 218619 (Folder FF294)
          includes images of the Stuyvesant Pear Tree
        - Fourth Avenue, 218620 (Folder FF295)
        - Fifth Avenue - Washington Square north to 14th Street, 218773 (Folder FF296)
        - Fifth Avenue - 14th to 22nd Street, 218775 (Folder FF297)
        - Fifth Avenue - 23rd to 30th Street, 218778 (Folder FF298)
        - Fifth Avenue - 31st to 38th Street, 218779 (Folder FF299)
        - Fifth Avenue - 38th to 43rd Street, 218780 (Folder FF300)
        - Fifth Avenue - 43rd to 50th Street, 218781 (Folder FF301)
        - Fifth Avenue - 50th to 56th Street, 218783 (Folder FF302)
        - Fifth Avenue - 57th to 60th Street, 218784 (Folder FF303)
        - Fifth Avenue - 60th to 80th Street, 218786 (Folder FF304)
        - Fifth Avenue - 80th Street and north, 218788 (Folder FF305)
        - Sixth Avenue, 218791 (Folder FF306)
        - Seventh Avenue, 218792 (Folder FF307)
        - Eighth Avenue, 218793 (Folder FF308)
        - Ninth Avenue, 218794 (Folder FF309)
        - Tenth Avenue, 218795 (Folder FF310)
        - Eleventh Avenue, 218796 (Folder FF311)
        - Twelfth Avenue, 218797 (Folder FF312)
    - Manhattan - Flat Material - Photos - Neighborhoods, 218798
      - Inwood and Manhattanville, 218799 (Folder FF313)
      - Times Square, 218801 (Folder FF314)
    - Manhattan - Flat Material - Photos - Parks and Gardens, 218802
      - Battery Park, 218803 (Folder FF314)
      - Bowling Green, 218804 (Folder FF316)
      - Bryant Park, 224777 (Folder FF317)
      - City Hall Park, 218805 (Folder FF318)
      - Central Park - General, 218806 (Folder FF319)
        includes activities such as skating, etc.
      - Central Park - Construction of Reservoir and Fountains, 218807 (Folder FF320)
      - Central Park - Statuary, 218808 (Folder FF321)
        includes views of the Obelisk being removed from Egypt
      - Inwood Hill Park, 218810 (Folder FF322)
      - Madison Square Park, 218811 (Folder FF323)
      - Riverside Park, 218812 (Folder FF324)
      - Union Square Park, 218813 (Folder FF325 and FF325.5)
        includes an image of the Metropolitan Sanitary Fair building, 1864.
      - Washington Square Park, 218814 (Folder FF326)
    - Manhattan - Flat Material - Photos - Buildings, 218857
      - Armories and Arsenals, 218858 (Folder FF327)
        Old Guard Armory, 14th St. and Fifth Avenue
        Seventh Regiment Armory
        71st Regiment Armory
        Shot Tower, Cliff Street
        Shot Tower, 53rd Street
        Tompkins Market Armory, Third Avenue and 6th St.
        22nd Regiment, Broadway and 67th St (including construction)
      - Churches and Synagogues -A-, 221103 (Folder FF328)
        Abyssinian Baptist Church
        All Nations, Church for
        All Saints Roman Catholic Church
        Ascension, Church of the
      - Churches and Synagogues -Adams-Parkhurst Presbyterian Church, 224956 (Folder FF329)
      - Churches and Synagogues -Amity Baptist Church, 224957 (Folder FF330)
      - Churches and Synagogues -B-, 224959 (Folder FF331)
        Baptist Temple Church
        Bedford Street Methodist Episcopal Church
        Bethel AME Church
        Bloomingdale Reformed Dutch Church
        Brick Presbyterian Church
        Broadway Tabernacle
        Central Presbyterian Church
      - Churches and Synagogues - C-D, 224960 (Folder FF332)
        Christ Apostolic Church of USA
        Christ Church
        Collegiate Reformed Church
        Collegiate Reformed Church of Harlem
        Covenant, Church of the
        Disciples, Church of the
        Deutsche Evangeliche Kirche
      - Churches and Synagogues - E-G, 225022 (Folder FF333)
        Emanu-el, Congregation
        Ephesus Seventh Day Adventist Church
        First Alliance Church
        First Sharon Baptist Church
        Forsythe Street Methodist Church
        Fort George Iglesia Presbiteriana
        Fort Washington Collegiate Church
        Fort Washington Heights Iglesia Presbiteriana
        Greater Metropolitan Baptist Church
        Greater Refuge Temple
      - Churches and Synagogues -Fifth Avenue Presbyterian Church, 225023 (Folder FF334)
      - Churches and Synagogues -Grace Church, 225024 (Folder FF335)
      - Churches and Synagogues -Holy Trinity, 225025 (Folder FF336)
      - Churches and Synagogues -H-L, 225027 (Folder FF337)
        Heavenly Rest, Church of the
        Holy Fathers Russian Orthodox Church
        Holy Rood, Church of the
        Jehovah's Witness Kingdom Hall, 609 W. 161st St.
        John Street Methodist Church
        LaGree Baptist Church
        Lord Jesus Christ of the Apostolic Faith, Church of the
      - Churches and Synagogues -M-, 225028 (Folder FF338)
        Madison Avenue Baptist Church
        Madison Square Presbyterian Church
        Manhattan, Iglesia Adventista del Septimo Dia de
        Memorial Baptist Church
        Messiah, Church of the
        Metropolitan AME Church
        Metropolitan Baptist Church
        Metropolitan Community United Methodist Church
        Mother AME Zion Church
        Mount Calvary United Methodist Church
        Mount Neboh Baptist Church
        Mount Olive Fire Baptized Holiness Church
        Mount Washington Presbyterian Church
      - Churches and Synagogues -N-R, 225029 (Folder FF339)
        North Dutch Church
        Our Lady of Mount Carmel, Church of
        Our Lady of Perpetual help, Church of
        Our Lady of the Scapular – St. Stephen, Church of
        Paulist Fathers, Church of the
        Prince of Peace Universal Tabernacle Spiritual Church
        Rendell Memorial Presbyterian Church
      - Churches and Synagogues -Sa-, 225030 (Folder FF340)
        St. Aloysius, Church of
        St. Ambrose Episcopal Church
        St. Andrew's Episcopal Church
        St. Bartholomew's Church
        St. James Presbyterian Church
        St. John the Evangelist, Episcopal Church of
        St. Mark's United Methodist Church
        St. Matthew's Lutheran Church
        St. Nicholas Greek Orthodox Church
        St. Patrick's Roman Catholic Cathedral
        St. Paul's Community Church
        St. Peter's Episcopal Church
        St. Stephen's United Methodist Church
        St. Thomas the Apostle, Church of
        Salem United Methodist Church
      - Churches and Synagogues -St. John the Divine, Cathedral Church of, 225031 (Folder FF341)
      - Churches and Synagogues -St. Mark's in the Bouwerie, 225033 (Folder FF342)
      - Churches and Synagogues -St. Paul's Chapel, 225034 (Folder FF343)
      - Churches and Synagogues -Se-Z, 225036 (Folder FF344)
        Second Canaan Baptist Church
        Sixteenth Street Baptist Church
        Trinity Chapel
        United Palace
        Wadsworth Avenue Baptist Church
        West Presbyterian Church
        Unidentified
      - Churches and Synagogues -Trinity Church, 225037 (Folder FF345)
        includes Trinity Churchyard and Alexander Hamilton's grave.
      - Clubs, Societies and Associations -A-L, 224653 (Folder FF346)
        American Seamen's Friend Society
        Bar Association Building
        Caledonian Club
        Century Club
        Chemist's Club
        Colony Club
        Down-Town Club
        Harmonie Club
        Knickerbocker Athletic Club
        Liederkranz Club
      - Clubs, Societies and Associations -M-Z, 225055 (Folder FF347)
        Manhattan Athletic Club
        Masonic Hall
        National Academy of Design
        Player's Club
        Road Driver's Association of New York
        Tammany Hall
        Union Club
        Union League Club
        University Club
        YMCA, 23rd Street and Fourth Avenue
      - Commercial & Financial -Banks, 224782 (Folder FF348)
        Bank of New York
        Bowery Savings Bank
        Colonial Bank
        Dry Dock Savings Bank
        Merchant's Bank
        (Drexel) Morgan & Co.
        Nassau Bank
        National Park Bank
        Tradesman's National Bank
      - Commercial & Financial -Exchanges, 225144 (Folder FF349)
        Consolidated Stock Exchange Cotton Exchange X New York Stock Exchange
      - Commercial & Financial -Insurance Companies, 225162 (Folder FF350)
        Equitable Life Insurance
        Hartford Accident Insurance Company
        Manhattan Life
        Metropolitan Life
        New York Life Insurance Company
      - Commercial & Financial -Markets, 225175 (Folder FF351)
        West Washington Market
      - Commercial & Financial -Office buildings A-B, 225176 (Folder FF352)
        One Wall Street
        American Express Building
        Bordon Building, 350 Madison
        Broaker & Schmidt, Public Accountants, 63 Fifth Ave. (interiors)
      - Commercial & Financial -Office buildings C-F, 225210 (Folder FF353)
        City Investing Building
        Corbin Building, John & Broadway
        Empire State Building
        Exchange Court Building, Exchange Place
        Flatiron Building (under construction)
        Fox Office Building & Studios, Tenth Ave. & 55th St.
      - Commercial & Financial -Office buildings M-S, 225211 (Folder FF354)
        Mercantile Building, 122 Fifth Avenue
        New Trust Company. 39 Wall Street
        St. Paul Building
        Singer Building
        Stockbroker's office interior 30 Broad Street
      - Commercial & Financial -Office buildings T-Z, 225214 (Folder FF355)
        United Nations
        Washington Building, 1 Broadway
        Woolworth Building
        World Trade Center
      - Commerical & Financial -Stores and Shops, 225224 (Folder FF356)
        A. T. Stewart's Dry Goods
        De Pinna Store, Fifth Avenue at 52nd St. 1956
        William P. Howell, Gunpowder Agent, 205 Front St
        R.H. Macy, Dry Goods
        Traphagen, Hunter & Co. Clothiers, 398 Bowery
      - Government- General, 224783 (Folder FF357)
        Barge office on Battery Place
        Castle Garden immigration station
        Custom House [Federal Hall National Monument] on Wall Street
        Custom House on Bowling Green
        Federal Office Building, 90 Church Street
        New York County Courthouse
        Second Circuit Court of Appeals
      - Government -City Hall in City Hall Park, 225232 (Folder FF358)
      - Government -Fire Department, 225233 (Folder FF359)
        157 East 67th Street-Engine Company 39, Hook and Ladder Company 16.
        Engine Company 33
        Fire Patrol 1
        Engine Company 9.
      - Government -Post Offices, 225234 (Folder FF360)
        Post office, Broadway and Park Row
        Post office, Seventh Avenue and 32nd Street.
      - Government -Prisons, 224784 (Folder FF361)
      - Hotels A-E, 225237 (Folder FF362)
        Hotel Albert
        Hotel Bellclaire
        Bennett House
        Hotel Brunswick
        Clarendon Hotel
        Continental Hotel
        Hotel de Ashe
        Hotel Earle
      - Hotels - Hotel Empire, 225238 (Folder FF363)
      - Hotels F-H (Folder FF364)
        Fort George Hotel
        Gilsey House
        Grand Hotel
        Holland House
      - Hotels - Gotham Hotel (Folder FF364.5)
      - Hotels I-L, 225239 (Folder FF365)
        Hotel Imperial
        Hotel Knickerbocker
        Knott Hotels Group
        Hotel Lafayette
        Hotel Lucerne
        Lafayette Place Hotel
      - Hotels M-N, 225241 (Folder FF366)
        Hotel Marie Antoinette
        Hotel Marlborough
        Hotel Martin
        Mount St. Vincent Hotel
        Murray Hill Hotel
        National Hotel
        Hotel Navarre
      - Hotels - Plaza Hotel, 225242 (Folder FF367)
        Plaza Hotel
      - Hotels Q-Z, 225243 (Folder FF368)
        Hotel St. Andrew
        Hotel Savoy
        Sinclair House
        Spingler House
        Hotel Touraine
        Hotel Victoria
        Walton House
        Windsor Hotel
      - Hotels - Waldorf Astoria (Folder FF369)
      - Institutions - Hospitals and Asylums, 224785 (Folder FF370)
        Bellevue Hospital
        Charity Hospital (Blackwell's Island)
        Floating Hospital
        Hospital for the Ruptured and Crippled
        House of Mercy
        Presbyterian Hospital
        St. Joseph's Orphan Asylum (formerly Nathaniel Prime mansion), East 89th Street
      - Libraries, 224786 (Folder FF371)
        Lenox Library
        Mercantile Library (under construction)
        New York Public Library, 42nd and Fifth (under construction)
      - Museums, 224787 (Folder FF372)
        Eden Musee
        Guggenheim Museum
        Metropolitan Museum of Art (including interiors)
        Museum of Natural History
        New-York Historical Society
      - Manufacturers & Warehouses I, 224788 (Folder FF373)
        Brewster & Co, Carriage Works
        Daniel Coger & Son, ship joiners, 480 Water St.
        Eagleson & Deveau Vermont Marbleworks, 427 W. 14th St.
        Irving & Son Carriage Factory, 118 W. 52nd St.
        Monahan's Xpress Company Depot, W.11th St. and 7th Ave
        Ben Moral, shoe manufacturer, 566 Broadway
        Nason Manufacturing Co., 71 Beekman St.
        Rhinelander Sugar House
        Steinway Piano warehouse
        Unidentified cigar factory, interior with workers
      - Manufacturers & Warehouses II (Folder FF374)
        Fairchild Bros. & Foster, manufacturing chemists, office interiors
        Unidentified hardware manufacturing firm
      - Manufacturers & Warehouses - Knickerbocker Storage Warehouse (Folder FF375)
        interiors and exteriors. Located on East 24th Street.
      - Monuments - General, 224821 (Folder FF376)
        Christopher Columbus Monument
        Horace Greeley Statue
        Sherman Statue (Central Park)
        Statue of Liberty
      - Monuments - Dewey Arch (Folder FF377)
      - Monuments - Grant's Tomb - General, 1887 and later (Folder FF378)
        includes dedication ceremonies
      - Monuments - Grant's Tomb - First building, 1885-1886 (Folder FF379)
      - Monuments - Grant's Tomb - Decoration Day, 1922 (Folder FF380)
      - Monuments - Washington Arch (Folder FF381)
        includes temporary arch on Fifth Ave. and permanent monument in Washington Square Park.
      - Printers & Publishers, 224822 (Folder FF382)
        Great American Printing Co., Beekman St. ca. 1871
        New York Herald, Broadway and 35th St. 1895
        New York Times, Park Row and Nassau St. 1872-73
        New York World
        New York World Telegram, 125 Barclay St.
        News Building, 216-236 42nd St.
      - Residences A-E, 224823 (Folder FF383)
        Abeel, John H., 127 Second Ave
        Audubon, John James, ca. 1912
        Bicknell, Frank Albert (studio interior)
        Brainerd, C. N., Kingsbridge Rd.
        Carnegie, Andrew (art gallery)
        Carrigan, Andrew, 114th St. and Riverside Dr.
        Cudlipp, Joseph, Broadway and 76th St.
        DeWitt, Peter, 11 St. Marks Place
      - Residences - Apthorpe, Charles Ward, West 91st Street (Folder FF384)
      - Residences - Astor, Mr. William (Folder FF385)
      - Residences - Babcock, Hamlin. On the East River between E. 75th and E. 76th Street (Folder FF386)
      - Residences - Boker, Carl F., 23 W. 76th Street, circa 1909 (Folder FF387)
        interiors
      - Residences - Bradhurst estate, W. 148th Street and St. Nicholas Avenue (Folder FF388)
      - Residences - Codwin, Elliot C., 18 West 21st Street (Folder FF389)
      - Residences F-H (Folder FF390)
        Fabri, Ernesto, 11 E. 62nd St.
        Gerry, Commodore Elbridge T., E. 60th St. and Fifth Ave.
        Goelet, Peter, 19th St. and Broadway
        Griswald, William E.S., 883 Fifth Ave. (interior)
        Harsen, Jacob, Tenth Ave. and 70th St.
      - Residences - Gracie Mansion - exteriors (Folder FF391)
        includes images by Pach Bros. photographers
      - Residences - Gracie Mansion - interiors (Folder FF392)
        mainly taken by Pach Bros. photographers ca. 1890
      - Residences - Grenzebach, John N., Third Avenue and East 75th Street - interiors (Folder FF393)
      - Residences - Hamilton Grange (Folder FF394)
        Estate of Alexander Hamilton, 143rd. Street and 10th Avenue, Harlem. Includes interiors, and a series of exterior photos from 1874.
      - Residences - Hammond, John Henry, 9 East 91st Street - interiors (Folder FF395)
      - Residences - Havemeyer, Theodore A., 244 Madison Ave. at 38th Street- interiors (Folder FF396)
      - Residences - Herbert, J. W., 835 Fifth Avenue - interior and exterior, 1913 (Folder FF397)
      - Residences - Huntington, Collis P., 57th Street and Fifth Ave. (Folder FF398)
      - Residences I-M (Folder FF399)
        Jones, Mary Mason, 1 East 57th Street (Marble Row)
        Kuttroff, Adolph, 17 E. 69th St.
        Leary, Countess Annie, 1032 Fifth Ave. (interiors, including dining room set for a Columbus Day dinner party)
        Meyer, John, farmhouse, Eighth Ave. and 133rd St. before 1877
        Mott, Jordon and Winifred, W. 54th St